Jackie Martin Papers
Jackie Martin Papers
- Negatives and contacts
  - Biographical negatives
    - Mama, Diddy and Bill; made at airport with 88 cent camera; Jackie Martin leaving for Paris (Box 47)
    - Diddy, Bill, Mom, and Pop, Aunt Timmis (Box 47)
    - Early negatives on Papa (Box 47)
    - A birthday party for Mama, USSH (Box 47)
    - Pop playing his monocello; Lola and Mom (Box 47)
    - General shots at USSH (Box 47)
    - Papa at Jackie's desk at Chicago Sun office in Press Building (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin at party for Mai Casey at Willard; Press gals, 2 4x5 (Box 47)
    - John Martin's grave stone, 1853-1917, 1 3x5 (Box 47)
    - Golden wedding anniversary, Mr. and Mrs. Martin, 1949 (Box 47)
    - Early family shots in Washington, Lincoln Park, 130 4x5, 5 3x5, 10 2x3, 4 1x2 (Box 47)
    - Nancy Lea Clements, model school graduate; group shot of party at Lincoln Park; also Jerry, Phil, Nancy Osgood, Billy (Box 47)
    - Family at Diddy and Bill's, 05 Jan 1947; Christmas 1947; total Martin-Clements-Pugh family; McL.L.; USSH and Lincoln Park; Phil, Bobby, and Penny home from Hollywood (Box 47)
    - Clements Family Christmas card; Nancy, Pish, Billy, Bill and Jerry; Mom and Diddy (Box 47)
    - Dr. and Mrs. Nabrit, Lecrutia Grady, Casey Blackburn, and Jackie Martin; Eleanor Roosevelt Award Dinner, 1964 (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin in front of Parco Hotel, 1944 (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin at Fort Meade with Colonel Currier; at Rogenette with 93rd Evacuation Hosptial; Monte Casale, Italy with Colonel Shaw (driver of jeep); Pompeii; Paris, Ginnie Stanley; Belmont with General Patch; Bruyeres with dead [German]; Rome; 11th Evacuation Hospital with Colonel Wilbur; Luxuiel Airport and Nazi plane; Rome Airport; with famous french woman-surgeon outside of Epinal (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin and Steve Kellogg at Sun office in Press Building (Box 47)
    - Last shot of Papa made by Bill Pugh at his and Diddy's house, USSH; Mama, Papa, Bill C., and Baby Doll; Papa's casket and flowers (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin shooting from truck in Naples, early August, 1944 (Box 47)
    - Jackie Martin test shots (Box 47)
  - Glass Plates, 132 total
    - Jackie Martin posing in basketball uniform, 1926; 2 5x7 (Box 48)
    - Jackie Martin running race, 1-6 (3x4); buys 1st car, 1-4 (1927) 3x4; Personal friends, 1-16 and contacts (4x5) (Box 48)
    - Phillip Martin Sr. at age 18, 1895; 1 4x5 (Box 48)
    - Family shots, 1-13 (4x5); 1-10 (4x5); Mr. and Mrs. Martin, 1-13 (4x5); early shots of Jackie Martin, 1-13 (4x5); Phil Jr. in office, 1-6 (4x5); Phillip Martin Sr.'s early family shots, 1-13 (4x5) (Box 48)
    - Times-Herald News Coverage, 1926; 1-15 and contacts (4x5); 1-14 and contacts (4x5); 1-15 and contacts (4x5); Personalities, 1-13 (4x5) (Box 48)
  - Sports
    - Army-Navy game (Box 49)
    - Max Baer's brother's Fight, NY (Box 49)
    - Fight (Box 49)
    - Marlboro; Marlboro Horse Show, Spil, etc, 2 rolls (Box 49)
    - Mountain Lake Tennis (Box 49)
    - New York bike race, See Negatives and contacts: Candids: Dance: La Argentina
    - Preakness (Box 49)
    - Race between War Admiral and Sea Biscuit, Pimlico (Box 49)
    - Tennis at Maryland University (Box 49)
    - Unlabeled, 2 rolls (Box 49)
  - Parties
    - WAAC birthday, 1947 (Box 49)
    - Women's National Press Club annual party, 1947; 5 rolls (Box 49)
    - Carrier boy's annual party, 2 rolls (Box 49)
    - Circulation Boy's Club Dinner, Willard (Box 49)
    - College boys at Mrs. Patterson's (Box 49)
    - Democratic Women's Club party (Box 49)
    - Mrs. Evalyn Walsh McLean's party, Mar 1940 (Box 49)
    - Eleanor Patterson's Christmas party (Box 49)
    - Press Club party, 1937 (Box 49)
    - Robert's "Gone With the Wind" party, Atlanta (Box 49)
    - Soviet Embassy party (Box 49)
    - Stunt party, 1940; 4 rolls (Box 49)
    - White House party practice (Box 49)
  - Editorial and feature coverage
    - Christmas shopping at Kann's (Box 49)
    - Chrysler trip (2 rolls); Palm Springs; Will Roger's Statue; with Virginia Campbell and Orchid (Box 49)
    - Corn stalks, our line of defense (Box 49)
    - Dunes, 1935 (Box 49)
    - Editorial shot: the need for girl's clubs (Box 49)
    - Farm scenes (Box 49)
    - Hauptman trial (Box 49)
    - Helsinki Parliament (Box 49)
    - Koop; Florida, Ladies Home Journal (Box 49)
    - School children and principal at Holtville, Alabama for Country Gentleman (Box 49)
    - Share croppers, 4 rolls (Box 49)
    - Test shots (my room) (Box 49)
    - Week-end series: rumble seat driving shot (Box 49)
    - Mother and child, See Negatives and contacts: Candids: Personalities: Clare Boothe Luce
    - New Penna R.R. electric train, See Negatives and contacts: Candids: Musicians and orchestras: Metropolitan Quartet
    - Orchid close-up, See Negatives and contacts: Sports: Max Baer's brother's Fight, NY
    - Rogersville doctor and nurse, See Negatives and contacts: Candids: Musicians and orchestras: Iturbi
  - Hollywood
    Probably in collection, but cannot find (04/28/2009)
    Binder:
    Carol Lombard
    Bea Lillie
    Gracie Allen
    "Hurricane" opening
    Pat O'Brien, Billie Burke, Fannie Brice, and Sophie Tucker
    Herbert Marshall
    Arabian Horses
    Powell and Blondell
    Dorothy Arzner
    Anita Louise
    Wendy Barrie
    Anna Sten
    Maxine Doyle, Preston Foster, Gene Raymond
    Helen Ferguson, Tyrone Power
    George Raft
    Freddie Bartholomew
    Jane Withers
    Fashion Show
    Unmarked sheets I and II
    Other:
    Josephine Baker, 1964
    Testimonial Dinner for Leslie Biffle
    Bil Pugh's funeral, 20 Aug 1963
    Delta Gamma exhibit A and B, 1960s